<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Photography | Core Fruition]]></title>
  <link href="https://mrrooni.com/fruitstandsoftware/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://mrrooni.com/fruitstandsoftware/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-10T09:28:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://mrrooni.com/fruitstandsoftware/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Fey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC 2012 Photo Walk Wrap-Up]]></title>
    <link href="https://mrrooni.com/fruitstandsoftware/blog/2012/06/21/wwdc-2012-photo-walk-wrap-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-21T10:57:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://mrrooni.com/fruitstandsoftware/blog/2012/06/21/wwdc-2012-photo-walk-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://500px.com/photo/8672882"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Oakland-Bay-Bridge-Pano.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2012/06/wwdc-2012-photo-walk/">WWDC 2012 Photo Walk sponsored by 500px</a> was a huge success! We had an incredible turnout that, quite honestly, blew me away.</p>

<p>As a last minute surprise we had the fine folks from <a href="http://www.speckproducts.com/iphone-case/iphone-4-case.html">Speck</a> come out to demonstrate their upcoming CandyShell Focus case for iPhone 4 and iPhone 4S. To cap it all off they handed out a bunch of them to the attendees. I&rsquo;ve had mine on my phone since the walk and I love it. I&rsquo;ll admit I don&rsquo;t do too much photography with my phone, but I have found myself using the stand for FaceTime calls and just for standing up the phone on my desk. If you&rsquo;d like more info on it you should get in touch with Erica on Twitter <a href="http://twitter.com/2bmighty">@2bmighty</a>, and tell her <a href="http://twitter.com/MrRooni">@MrRooni</a> sent you. (Not for any good reason, but let&rsquo;s be honest, it&rsquo;s just fun to end a sentence with, &ldquo;tell them I sent you&rdquo;)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/CandyShellFocusBySpeck.jpg"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/CandyShellFocusBySpeck.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>We also had the guys from <a href="http://macphun.com">MacPhun</a> show up and very generously offer a free license to their new photography product, <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/snapheal/id480623975?mt=12">Snapheal</a>, to everyone who attended. If you went on the walk and you&rsquo;d like a copy of Snapheal just send an email to me (michael [at] this domain) and Alex Tsepko (atsepko [at] macphun) with your favorite photo from the walk. I haven&rsquo;t actually had a chance to try it out yet, but I heard from a few people on the walk that use MacPhun&rsquo;s other photography products and love them.</p>

<p>As you know, for those that participated in the walk, the editors at <a href="http://500px.com/">500px</a> are going to choose their two favorite photographs from the walk and upgrade those photographer&rsquo;s accounts to Plus and Awesome. All you have to do is upload your photos to your 500px account and tag the photos with the tag <a href="http://500px.com/search?tag=WWDC-photowalk">wwdc-photowalk</a>. The last day to upload your best shots for a chance to get your account upgraded is <del>Thursday, June 21st</del> TODAY. You can find my shots in a set on 500px here: <a href="http://500px.com/MrRooni/sets/wwdc_2012_photo_walk_sponsored_by_500px">WWDC 2012 Photo Walk sponsored by 500px</a>. If you&rsquo;d like to see all my photos from WWDC you can find them here: <a href="http://500px.com/MrRooni/sets/wwdc_2012">WWDC 2012</a></p>

<p>I know I mentioned it above, but we really did have a great turnout. So good in fact, that people are already asking me to organize one for next year. To that end I&rsquo;ve created a new Twitter account dedicated to the walk: <a href="http://twitter.com/WWDCPhotoWalk">@WWDCPhotoWalk</a>. You should follow that account for any and all info on the next walk.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who came out, you all exceeded my expectations, and I&rsquo;ll see you next year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
