<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | Core Fruition]]></title>
  <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//"/>
  <updated>2014-06-10T09:28:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Fey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC 2012 Photo Walk Wrap-Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2012/06/21/wwdc-2012-photo-walk-wrap-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-21T10:57:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2012/06/21/wwdc-2012-photo-walk-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://500px.com/photo/8672882"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Oakland-Bay-Bridge-Pano.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2012/06/wwdc-2012-photo-walk/">WWDC 2012 Photo Walk sponsored by 500px</a> was a huge success! We had an incredible turnout that, quite honestly, blew me away.</p>

<p>As a last minute surprise we had the fine folks from <a href="http://www.speckproducts.com/iphone-case/iphone-4-case.html">Speck</a> come out to demonstrate their upcoming CandyShell Focus case for iPhone 4 and iPhone 4S. To cap it all off they handed out a bunch of them to the attendees. I&rsquo;ve had mine on my phone since the walk and I love it. I&rsquo;ll admit I don&rsquo;t do too much photography with my phone, but I have found myself using the stand for FaceTime calls and just for standing up the phone on my desk. If you&rsquo;d like more info on it you should get in touch with Erica on Twitter <a href="http://twitter.com/2bmighty">@2bmighty</a>, and tell her <a href="http://twitter.com/MrRooni">@MrRooni</a> sent you. (Not for any good reason, but let&rsquo;s be honest, it&rsquo;s just fun to end a sentence with, &ldquo;tell them I sent you&rdquo;)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/CandyShellFocusBySpeck.jpg"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/CandyShellFocusBySpeck.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>We also had the guys from <a href="http://macphun.com">MacPhun</a> show up and very generously offer a free license to their new photography product, <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/snapheal/id480623975?mt=12">Snapheal</a>, to everyone who attended. If you went on the walk and you&rsquo;d like a copy of Snapheal just send an email to me (michael [at] this domain) and Alex Tsepko (atsepko [at] macphun) with your favorite photo from the walk. I haven&rsquo;t actually had a chance to try it out yet, but I heard from a few people on the walk that use MacPhun&rsquo;s other photography products and love them.</p>

<p>As you know, for those that participated in the walk, the editors at <a href="http://500px.com/">500px</a> are going to choose their two favorite photographs from the walk and upgrade those photographer&rsquo;s accounts to Plus and Awesome. All you have to do is upload your photos to your 500px account and tag the photos with the tag <a href="http://500px.com/search?tag=WWDC-photowalk">wwdc-photowalk</a>. The last day to upload your best shots for a chance to get your account upgraded is <del>Thursday, June 21st</del> TODAY. You can find my shots in a set on 500px here: <a href="http://500px.com/MrRooni/sets/wwdc_2012_photo_walk_sponsored_by_500px">WWDC 2012 Photo Walk sponsored by 500px</a>. If you&rsquo;d like to see all my photos from WWDC you can find them here: <a href="http://500px.com/MrRooni/sets/wwdc_2012">WWDC 2012</a></p>

<p>I know I mentioned it above, but we really did have a great turnout. So good in fact, that people are already asking me to organize one for next year. To that end I&rsquo;ve created a new Twitter account dedicated to the walk: <a href="http://twitter.com/WWDCPhotoWalk">@WWDCPhotoWalk</a>. You should follow that account for any and all info on the next walk.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who came out, you all exceeded my expectations, and I&rsquo;ll see you next year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indie+Relief an Amazing Success!]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2010/01/22/indierelief-an-amazing-success/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-22T10:31:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2010/01/22/indierelief-an-amazing-success</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/ir_500.png"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/ir_500.png" alt="Indie+Relief Banner" /></a></p>

<p>Many congrats to everyone who participated in Indie+Relief. Over $143,872 was raised for the people of Haiti through various charities!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.indierelief.com/">http://www.indierelief.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indie+Relief]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2010/01/17/indierelief/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-17T10:23:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2010/01/17/indierelief</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://indierelief.com/"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/ir_500.png" alt="Indie+Relief Banner" /></a></p>

<p>For those that may not have heard, <a href="http://twitter.com/justin">Justin Williams</a> has organized a great effort to provide financial relief to the people of Haiti. Set to take place throughout the day on January 20th, all the proceeds from the sale of participating software will be donated to Haiti. We here at <a href="http://www.nothirst.com/">No Thirst Software</a> are participating with sales of <a href="http://www.nothirst.com/moneywell/">MoneyWell</a> and <a href="http://www.nothirst.com/debtquencher/">Debt Quencher</a>. For a full list of participating software please check out the <a href="http://www.indierelief.com/">Indie+Relief</a> website.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a great cause and I know that I will be checking the list for software that&rsquo;s on my &ldquo;to buy&rdquo; list. I suggest that you do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well That Didn't Take Long]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/06/29/well-that-didnt-take-long/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-29T15:22:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/06/29/well-that-didnt-take-long</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As you can see we are now flying under a new banner: Core Fruition!  In less than two hours from my last post I had <a href="http://twitter.com/pgor/status/2389414409">the answer</a> to my naming quandary from <a href="http://twitter.com/pgor">Paul Goracke</a>, and I can&rsquo;t thank him enough.</p>

<p>When I saw Paul&rsquo;s suggestion my first thought was, &ldquo;That&rsquo;s an awesome name!&rdquo;. My second thought was, &ldquo;That sounds really close to <a href="http://www.coreint.org/">another popular Cocoa site</a>&hellip;&rdquo;  Not wanting to step on any toes, I decided to throw the name into some focus testing, asking a bunch of high ranking folks for their gut reaction.  Here are the results:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://twitter.com/MRRSoftware/">Mickey Roberson</a>: &ldquo;That&rsquo;s not bad&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/bdudney">Bill Dudney</a>: &ldquo;Frution is too &lsquo;hard to read&rsquo;, but not gut reaction is I like it &hellip; cool name&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/dtm3dd">Danny Greg</a>: &ldquo;rip off of core intuition, other then that &ndash; nice&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/jeff_lamarche">Jeff LaMarche</a>: &ldquo;I like it.&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/daveverwer">Dave Verwer</a>: &ldquo;I like Core Fruition&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/BrentWatson">Brent Watson</a>: &ldquo;I like it&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/mzarra">Marcus Zarra</a>: &ldquo;I like it. Makes me think of learning cocoa&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>As you can see, most folks liked it with only Danny giving me the reaction I was afraid of, which wasn&rsquo;t enough to keep me from pulling the trigger.  I&rsquo;d like to thank everyone for submitting names and cool ideas, and especially Paul for hooking me up with a winner.  Now, if some intrepid graphic designer would like to hook me up with a sweet logo&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am Not a Name Thief]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/06/29/i-am-not-a-name-thief/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-29T10:25:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/06/29/i-am-not-a-name-thief</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not intentionally, anyway.  First a little back story: When I was trying to decide on a name for this blog I would come up with what I thought was a great name and then plug it into Google to make sure that it wasn&rsquo;t already taken.  Most of the time I would find a blog that already had the same name and move on to a new round of brainstorming.  When I arrived at the name &ldquo;Cocoa Nut&rdquo; I thought for sure it would be taken.  I did a <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=%22cocoa+nut%22">quick search</a> but found no hits for that name having anything to do with programming in the first few pages of search results.  I thought, much to my amazement, that I had struck blog naming gold, I couldn&rsquo;t believe my luck!</p>

<p>[caption id=&ldquo;attachment_262&rdquo; align=&ldquo;aligncenter&rdquo; width=&ldquo;632&rdquo; caption=&ldquo;Apparently my brain decided to ignore the third entry on the first page of Google results&rdquo;]<a href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2009/06/i-am-not-a-name-thief/cocoa-nut-in-google/"><img src="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/Cocoa-Nut-in-Google.png" alt="Apparently my brain decided to ignore the third entry on the first page of Google results" /></a>[/caption]</p>

<p>Fast forward to last week.  I was looking up some show notes on the <a href="http://www.mac-developer-network.com/">Mac Developer Network</a> when I noticed the blog roll on the side of the page.  Curious if my blog was listed there (I had submitted it to Scotty a while back) I took a quick glance through the list and saw <a href="http://cocoa-nut.de/">Cocoa Nut</a> sandwiched between <a href="http://www.wilshipley.com/blog/">Call Me Fishmeal</a> and <a href="http://cocoasamurai.blogspot.com/">Cocoa Samurai</a>.  I clicked through expecting to be greeted with my blog&rsquo;s homepage but was instead taken to a different Cocoa Nut.</p>

<p>[caption id=&ldquo;attachment_263&rdquo; align=&ldquo;aligncenter&rdquo; width=&ldquo;762&rdquo; caption=&ldquo;The original Cocoa Nut&rdquo;]<a href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2009/06/i-am-not-a-name-thief/original-cocoa-nut-header/"><img src="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/Original-Cocoa-Nut-Header.png" alt="The original Cocoa Nut" /></a>[/caption]</p>

<p>Astounded, I quickly checked his archives, sure that he had shown up on the scene after me and had not been thorough enough in his search for naming collisions.  2006.  His first post was from 2006.  My first post was in 2008.  I was sunk.</p>

<p>So back to the title of this post: I am not a name thief.  I am currently searching for a new moniker for this blog.  Yes, I could make the argument that in a fully qualified world his Cocoa Nut and my Cocoa Nut are in completely different namespaces and that they don&rsquo;t collide, but that&rsquo;s BS and everyone would know it.</p>

<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;d like to suggest a name, please feel free.  Otherwise, I will be thinking and Googling until I come up with something that no one else has thought of yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
