<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Downloads | Core Fruition]]></title>
  <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/categories/downloads/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//"/>
  <updated>2014-06-10T09:28:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Fey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Awesomeness That Is Bodega]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2010/01/17/the-awesomeness-that-is-bodega/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-17T12:18:01-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2010/01/17/the-awesomeness-that-is-bodega</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://appbodega.com/"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/Bodega-300x300.png" alt="" /></a>Let&rsquo;s get one thing out of the way first thing: I&rsquo;m a big fan of <a href="http://appbodega.com/">Bodega</a> and have been since I heard about it firsthand from the guys at <a href="http://centrix.ca/">centrix.ca</a> during WWDC 2009.</p>

<p>Bodega is a free Mac application that helps you discover and download Mac applications. It is built in the spirit of great software sites like <a href="http://www.macupdate.com/">MacUpdate</a>, but takes the experience and puts a great looking Cocoa wrapper around it. Make no mistake, this project is a big undertaking with a lot of moving parts and a lot of coordination between those parts. Yet with steady progress and determination these guys are really crafting something cool.</p>

<p>The impetus for this particular blog post is to gush about what I think is Bodega&rsquo;s killer feature: keeping track of and installing updates for the applications installed on your computer. I really like <a href="http://sparkle.andymatuschak.org/">Andy Matuschack&rsquo;s Sparkle framework</a>, but one of the necessary evils of that framework is that it doesn&rsquo;t notify you that there is an update for a particular app until you run that app. When I launch an application it is done with the intention of performing a task immediately, but if there&rsquo;s an update for that particular app I am yanked out of my workflow to deal with the question of updating the app first. Yes, I can continue to work, but in the back of my mind I&rsquo;m thinking about how I don&rsquo;t have the latest version of the software that I am currently using, and it bugs me.</p>

<p>Enter Bodega. Once every few weeks I will launch Bodega and click on the Applications section in its sidebar which presents me with a list of all the software currently installed on my system*. The killer feature is that Bodega scans all of the Sparkle feeds in these apps and will tell me if there&rsquo;s an update for any of them. With two clicks (one to download and one to install) I can download and install any of the updates that I want. This simple process greatly reduces the chance that the next time I launch an app I will be presented with the option to download and install an update, Bodega has already taken care of it for me.</p>

<p>If you haven&rsquo;t <a href="http://appbodega.com/">downloaded Bodega</a> yet I highly recommend that you do and take it for a spin. If you&rsquo;re a developer and you haven&rsquo;t <a href="http://appbodega.com/Developers.php">submitted your software to Bodega</a>, I highly recommend that you do that too.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/ScreenshotThumb3.png"><img src="http://www.fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/ScreenshotThumb3.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<pre><code>Downloading and installing updates (Stolen shamelessly from the Bodega website)
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>Bodega is opt-in for developers, so if a developer hasn&rsquo;t submitted their software to the Bodega site it won&rsquo;t know about that software on your computer.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ParseKit]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/07/06/parsekit/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-06T13:19:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/07/06/parsekit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While I don&rsquo;t have an immediate need for ParseKit, I&rsquo;m fairly certain that it&rsquo;s going to come in very handy in the future.  Written by <a href="https://twitter.com/itod">Todd Ditchendorf</a>, the framework offers:</p>

<blockquote><ol>
<li><p> <strong><a href="http://parsekit.com/tokenization.html">String Tokenization</a></strong> via the Objective-C PKTokenizer and PKToken classes.</p></li>
<li><p> <strong>Language Parsing via Objective-C</strong> &ndash; An Objective-C parser-building API (the PKParserclass and sublcasses).</p></li>
<li><p> <strong><a href="http://parsekit.com/grammars.html">Parser Generation via Grammars</a></strong> &ndash; Generate an Objective-C parser for your custom language using a high-level grammar syntax (similar to yacc or ANTLR). While parsing, the parser will provide callbacks to your Objective-C code..</p></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p>Head on over to the <a href="http://parsekit.com/">ParseKit </a>website to download it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[UICatalog]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/04/03/uicatalog/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-03T16:15:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/04/03/uicatalog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reading through <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Beginning-iPhone-Development-Exploring-SDK/dp/1430216263/">Beginning iPhone Development</a> by <a href="http://twitter.com/davemark">Dave Mark</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/jeff_lamarche">Jeff LaMarche</a> I came across his handy link to a fantastic piece of iPhone development sample code: <a href="https://developer.apple.com/iphone/library/samplecode/UICatalog/index.html">UICatalog</a>.</p>

<p>UICatalog is an Xcode project that uses all of the UI elements contained in iPhone&rsquo;s UIKit framework.  There are quite a few great nuggets that this code produces such as:</p>

<p><a href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2009/04/uicatalog/picture-1/"><img src="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/picture-1.png" alt="UICatalog1" /></a><a href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2009/04/uicatalog/picture-2/"><img src="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/picture-2.png" alt="UICatalog2" /></a><a href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/2009/04/uicatalog/picture-3/"><img src="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/picture-3.png" alt="UICatalog3" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Typinator and Xcode]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/03/18/typinator-and-xcode/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-18T12:59:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/03/18/typinator-and-xcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently acquired a free license of <a href="http://www.macility.com/products/typinator/">Typinator</a> through <a href="http://www.macheist.com/">MacHeist</a> and have been loving it.  I put together a set of abbreviations for the text macros that  Xcode provides and it has made my coding life much easier.  A few folks have asked why I&rsquo;m not using xctxtmacros and the truth is that I didn&rsquo;t know about them.  Either way, Typinator is working great.</p>

<p>You can download my set of <a href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com/blog/?attachment_id=212">Xcode Abbreviations here</a>.  Please note that it&rsquo;s extremely limited as I only included those macros that I need most often.  Leave a comment if there are any that you think I&rsquo;m missing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cocoaFusion:The new podcast all about Cocoa]]></title>
    <link href="http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/01/11/cocoafusionthe-new-podcast-all-about-cocoa/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-11T10:15:01-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://fruitstandsoftware.com//blog/2009/01/11/cocoafusionthe-new-podcast-all-about-cocoa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those of you waiting for the next great thing in Cocoa development podcasts I humbly submit <a href="http://www.cocoafusion.net/">cocoaFusion:</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.cocoafusion.net/">cocoaFusion:</a> is hosted by Kevin Hoctor of <a href="http://nothirst.com/moneywell/">MoneyWell</a> fame, and Danny Greg the lead developer on <a href="http://www.realmacsoftware.com/">Realmac Software</a>&rsquo;s most recent release, <a href="http://www.realmacsoftware.com/littlesnapper/">LittleSnapper</a>.  The pair decided to start a podcast of their own after being introduced on one of <a href="http://twitter.com/macdevnet">Scotty&rsquo;s</a> excellent <a href="http://www.mac-developer-network.com/">Mac Developer Network</a> shows.</p>

<p>The idea behind <a href="http://www.cocoafusion.net/">cocoaFusion:</a> is for each Kevin and Danny to cover a coding problem that they&rsquo;ve faced down since the last episode.  The first episode has Kevin relating his experiences with <a href="http://developer.apple.com/DOCUMENTATION/Cocoa/Reference/Foundation/Classes/NSDateFormatter_Class/index.html">NSDateFormatter</a> while Danny goes in depth on <a href="http://developer.apple.com/documentation/Cocoa/Reference/NSPredicateEditor_class/index.html">NSPredicateEditor</a>.</p>

<p>While the pair admits to some rough edges in the first episode, the overall quality of the show&rsquo;s production and the ease with which Danny and Kevin relate to each other makes for a fantastic show that&rsquo;s a pleasure to listen to.</p>

<p>cocoaFusion: can be found on the web at <a href="http://www.cocoafusion.net/">cocoafusion.net</a> and in iTunes by following <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=301888038">this link</a>.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;d like to hear more from Kevin you can read his blog, <a href="http://kevinhoctor.blogspot.com/">Entrepreneurial Seduction</a> or <a href="http://twitter.com/kevinhoctor">follow him on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Danny&rsquo;s musings can be found on <a href="http://dannygreg.com/">his blog at dannygreg.com</a> and also on <a href="http://twitter.com/dtm3dd">his Twitter page</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
